Senator & Mrs. Whitney N. Seymour Jr. Papers: Records Relating to the Storm King Case, 1962-1978
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
Senator & Mrs. Whitney N. Seymour Jr. Papers: Records Relating to the Storm King Case
1962 - 1978
Senator & Mrs. Whitney N. Seymour Jr.
NPKMC-222-081
4 Linear Feet
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
As advocates of the environment and members of Scenic Hudson, Inc., founded in 1963, Senator and Mrs. Seymour dedicated their time and efforts to the preservation of Storm King Mountain, directly confronting the Consolidated Edison Company’s proposed pumped storage facility at Storm King Mountain, near Cornwall, New York. The records consist of correspondence, clippings, legal documents, agenda and minutes of meetings, memoranda, studies, reports, publicity materials, printed matter, and maps.
Related Collections
Alexander Saunders Papers: Records Relating to the Storm King Case, 1962 - 1966
Cornwall Pumped Storage Pumped Storage Collection, 1953 - 1981
Grim Collection: Hudson River Fisheries Investigation, 1965 - 1968
Hudson River Conservation Society, Inc. Collection, 1930 - 1980
Hudson River Environmental Society Collection, 1963 - 2005
Hudson River Valley Greenway Council Collection, 1989 - 1996
Hudson Valley GREEN Collection, 1981 - 2002
On the River Collection, 1986 - 1993
Scenic Hudson, Inc. Administrative History Collection, 1960 - 2000
Scenic Hudson Decision Hearings Transcripts Collection, 1977 - 1980
Scenic Hudson Collection: Records relating to the Storm King Case, 1963 - 1981
Collection Overview
The Seymour collection consists of materials relating to the landmark environmental law case that opposed the Consolidated Edison Company’s proposed pumped storage facility at Storm King Mountain, near Cornwall, New York. The records that the Seymour’s collected consist of correspondence, legal documents, clippings, agenda and minutes of meetings, memoranda, studies, reports, publicity materials, printed matter, and photographs.
Acquisitions Information
Scenic Hudson, Inc. presented the records to the Marist College Library in 1982.
Historical Note
In September 1962, the Consolidated Edison Company announced plans to build a pumped storage facility, the largest of its kind in the world, at Storm King Mountain near Cornwall, New York. The initial application for license to construct the plant was filed with the Federal Power Commission in January 1963. On November 8, 1963, a small group of concerned citizens met at the home of Carl Carmer and formed the Scenic Hudson Preservation Conference to fight the pumped storage project on the grounds that it posed a threat to the Cornwall water supply and Hudson River fisheries as well as to scenic and historic Storm King Mountain.
Senator and Mrs. Seymour were among the concerned citizens who helped form the foundation of the Scenic Hudson Preservation Conference. Mr. Seymour, a 1947 graduate of Princeton, received his J.D. from Yale Law School in 1950. In 1966 he was elected to the New York State Senate, representing the Southern District of New York. Senator Seymour was a strong proponent of the environment and dedicated much of his time and efforts to preserve Storm King Mountain. Mrs. Seymour was also a major player in the fight against Con Ed. As a member of Scenic Hudson’s Executive Committee she organized meetings, drafted correspondence, and rallied others to back their organization.
With the help of people like the Seymour’s, Scenic Hudson Preservation Conference and Con Ed were able to reach a settlement some 17 years after the original proposal was made. When all was said and done Consolidated Edison agreed to drop the plan for the Storm King Facility.
The lengthy and controversial case set important precedents in environmental law and is generally credited with spawning the modern environmental movement.
Restrictions to Access
There are no restrictions on this collection
Collection is arranged into seven series: 1. General Correspondence, 2. Clippings, 3. Scenic Hudson Preservation Conference, 4. Printed Matter, 5. Legal Material, 6. Statements, Radio and TV Reports, Released, Magazine Articles, Memos, and 7. Subject Files and Misc.
Materials in these series are either arranged chronologically or by subject.
- 1. General Correspondence, 1963 - 1978; 1; 0.3 Linear Feet Box: 1
  Incoming and outgoing correspondence of Mr. and Mrs. Seymour concerning the Storm King Case, also included are letters from Con Ed to Senator Seymour, as well as general correspondence between members of Scenic Hudson and the outside community.
  Chronological
  - Correspondence - 12/11/63 (Folder 1, Box 1)
  - Correspondence - 2/4/65 (Folder 2, Box 1)
  - Correspondence - March 1966 (Folder 3, Box 1)
  - Correspondence - April 1966 (Folder 4, Box 1)
  - Correspondence - May 1966 (Folder 5, Box 1)
  - Correspondence - June 1966 (Folder 6, Box 1)
  - Correspondence - July 1966 (Folder 7, Box 1)
  - Correspondence - August 1966 (Folder 8, Box 1)
  - Correspondence - Sept. 1966 (Folder 9, Box 1)
  - Correspondence - Oct. 1966 (Folder 10, Box 1)
  - Correspondence - Nov. 1966 (Folder 11, Box 1)
  - Correspondence - Dec. 1966 (Folder 12, Box 1)
  - Correspondence - Jan. 1967 (Folder 13, Box 1)
  - Correspondence - Feb. 1967 (Folder 14, Box 1)
  - Correspondence - March 1967 (Folder 15, Box 1)
  - Correspondence - April 1967 (Folder 16, Box 1)
  - Correspondence - May 1967 (Folder 17, Box 1)
  - Correspondence - June 1967 (Folder 18, Box 1)
  - Correspondence - August 1967 (Folder 19, Box 1)
  - Correspondence - Sept. 1967 (Folder 20, Box 1)
  - Correspondence - October 1967 (Folder 21, Box 1)
  - Correspondence - Nov. 1967 (Folder 22, Box 1)
  - Correspondence - Jan. 1968 (Folder 23, Box 1)
  - Correspondence - Feb. 1968 (Folder 24, Box 1)
  - Correspondence - March 1968 (Folder 25, Box 1)
  - Correspondence - April 1968 (Folder 26, Box 1)
  - Correspondence - May 1968 (Folder 27, Box 1)
  - Correspondence - June 1968 (Folder 28, Box 1)
  - Correspondence - July 1968 (Folder 29, Box 1)
  - Correspondence - Aug. 1968 (Folder 30, Box 1)
  - Correspondence - Sept. 1968 (Folder 31, Box 1)
  - Correspondence - Oct. 1968 (Folder 32, Box 1)
  - Correspondence - Nov. 1968 (Folder 33, Box 1)
  - Correspondence - Dec. 1968 (Folder 34, Box 1)
  - Correspondence - Jan. 1969 (Folder 35, Box 1)
  - Correspondence - March 1969 (Folder 36, Box 1)
  - Correspondence - April 1969 (Folder 37, Box 1)
  - Correspondence - May 1969 (Folder 38, Box 1)
  - Correspondence - June 1969 (Folder 39, Box 1)
  - Correspondence - July 1969 (Folder 40, Box 1)
  - Correspondence - August 1969 (Folder 41, Box 1)
  - Correspondence - Sept. 1969 (Folder 42, Box 1)
  - Correspondence - Oct. 1969 (Folder 43, Box 1)
  - Correspondence - Nov. 1969 (Folder 44, Box 1)
  - Correspondence - Dec. 1969 (Folder 45, Box 1)
  - Correspondence - Feb. 1970 (Folder 46, Box 1)
  - Correspondence - April 1970 (Folder 47, Box 1)
  - Correspondence - August 1970 (Folder 48, Box 1)
  - Correspondence - Sept. 1970 (Folder 49, Box 1)
  - Correspondence - April 1973 (Folder 50, Box 1)
  - Correspondence - April/May 1974 (Folder 51, Box 1)
  - Correspondence - May/June 1978 (Folder 52, Box 1)
  - Correspondence - Undated, Misc.&Rough Drafts (Folder 53, Box 1)
- 2. Clippings, 1962 - 1970; 2; 0.3 Linear Feet Box: 2
  Bound and loose newspaper clippings, arranged in rough chronological order; clippings from specific local newspapers; and clippings on particular topics.
  - Clippings - 1962 (Folder 1, Box 2)
  - Clippings - 1965 (Folder 2, Box 2)
  - Clippings - 1966 (Folder 3, Box 2)
  - Clippings - 1967 (Folder 4, Box 2)
  - Clippings - 1968 (Folder 5, Box 2)
  - Clippings - 1969 (Folder 6, Box 2)
  - Clippings - 1970 (Folder 7, Box 2)
  - Clippings - Undated (Folder 8, Box 2)
- 3. Scenic Hudson Preservation Conference, 1966 - 1970; 3; 1 Linear Foot Boxes: 3 - 6
  S.H.P.C. materials such as agenda and minutes of meetings, bulletins, financial reports, mailing lists, newsletters, fundraising materials, drafts of correspondence, and conservation dinner programs and seating lists.
  By subject and chronological
  - SHPC Bulletin #13, 3/3/66 (Folder 1, Box 3)
  - Bulletin #14, 3/31/66 (Folder 2, Box 3)
  - Bulletin #15, 5/17/66 (Folder 3, Box 3)
  - Bulletin #16, 6/1/66 (Folder 4, Box 3)
  - Bulletin #17, 7/7/66 (Folder 5, Box 3)
  - Bulletin #18, 8/15/66 (Folder 6, Box 3)
  - Bulletin #19, 9/20/66 (Folder 7, Box 3)
  - Special Bulletin, 11/7/66 (Folder 8, Box 3)
  - Bulletin #20, 1/4/67 (Folder 9, Box 3)
  - Bulletin #21, 1/13/67 (Folder 10, Box 3)
  - Bulletin #22, 3/28/67 (Folder 11, Box 3)
  - Bulletin #23, 4/25/67 (Folder 12, Box 3)
  - Bulletin #24, 6/13/67 (Folder 13, Box 3)
  - Bulletin #26, August 1968 (Folder 14, Box 3)
  - Bulletin #27, Oct. 1968 (Folder 15, Box 3)
  - Bulletin #28, Jan. 1969 (Folder 16, Box 3)
  - Bulletin #29, 2/11/69 (Folder 17, Box 3)
  - Bulletin #30 (Folder 18, Box 3)
  - Special Bulletin, 10/2/68 (Folder 19, Box 3)
  - Scenic Hudson News - Clippings, 1971 (Folder 20, Box 3)
  - Scenic Hudson News, 11/1/71 (Folder 21, Box 3)
  - SHPC News, Fall 1972 (Folder 22, Box 3)
  - Scenic Hudson News, Fall 1973 (Folder 23, Box 3)
  - Scenic Hudson News, Spring 1974 (Folder 24, Box 3)
  - Scenic Hudson News, Fall 1974 (Folder 25, Box 3)
  - Scenic Hudson News, Spring 1975 (Folder 26, Box 3)
  - Scenic Hudson News, Autumn 1975 (Folder 27, Box 3)
  - Scenic Hudson News, Autumn 1976 (Folder 28, Box 3)
  - Scenic Hudson News, Autumn 1977 (Folder 29, Box 3)
  - Scenic Hudson News - Energy Update, Autumn 1977 (Folder 30, Box 3)
  - Scenic Hudson News, Spring 1977 (Folder 31, Box 3)
  - Scenic Hudson News, Fall 1978 (Folder 32, Box 3)
  - Scenic Hudson News, Spring 1978 (Folder 33, Box 3)
  - SHPC Info Kit, The Preservation of Storm King Mt. (Folder 34, Box 3)
  - Storm King Fact Sheet (Folder 35, Box 3)
  - SHPC - Storm King Fact Sheet (Folder 36, Box 3)
  - The Issue at Storm King Mountain (Folder 37, Box 3)
  - Background Memo on the Issue Creating the Storm over Storm King, March 1966 (Folder 38, Box 3)
  - Progress Memo to SHPC Activists (Folder 39, Box 3)
  - Memo, 7/13/66 (Folder 40, Box 3)
  - Memo for the Information of Editors, 10/17/66 (Folder 41, Box 3)
  - Memo to Scenic Hudson Committee Members, 2/10/67 (Folder 42, Box 3)
  - Memo re: Expenditures, 1966 - 1967 (Folder 43, Box 3)
  - Memo to Officers of SHPC, 4/13/67 (Folder 44, Box 3)
  - Memo from Jim Cope, 6/21/67 (Folder 45, Box 3)
  - Memo to SHPC Board Members…7/18/67 (Folder 46, Box 3)
  - Memo to members of SHPC, 8/1/67 (Folder 47, Box 3)
  - Memo to Officers&Committee Members, 8/14/67 (Folder 48, Box 3)
  - Memo to Editors from SHPC, 8/23/67 (Folder 49, Box 3)
  - Memo to Editors from SHPC, 8/30/67 (Folder 50, Box 3)
  - Memo to Executive Committee Members, 9/7/67 (Folder 51, Box 3)
  - Memo, 9/21/67 (Folder 52, Box 3)
  - Memo re: Schedule for Nov. 18th Voyage, 11/2/67 (Folder 53, Box 3)
  - Memo: Report on the Hudson River Fishermen’s Association (Folder 54, Box 3)
  - Memo re: Dinner to Honor L.O. Rothschild, 5/15/68 (Folder 55, Box 3)
  - Memo: Planning for the Event; List of Invitees, 6/7/68 (Folder 56, Box 3)
  - Memo re: Decisions at Century Club Meeting, 6/13/68 (Folder 57, Box 3)
  - Memo re: Mid-Year Report on Scenic Hudson Fund-Raising Campaign, 7/15/68 (Folder 58, Box 3)
  - Memo re: Oram Memorandum, 7/17/68 (Folder 59, Box 3)
  - Special Memo to Groups Associated w/ Scenic Hudson in the fight To save Storm King, 8/9/68 (Folder 60, Box 3)
  - Memo re: New Round on Storm King, 8/12/68 (Folder 61, Box 3)
  - Memo to Editors from SHPC, 9/18/68 (Folder 62, Box 3)
  - Memo from the Staff, 9/19/68 (Folder 63, Box 3)
  - Memo re: Conversation w/ Stephen Duggan (Folder 64, Box 3)
  - Memo re: Fund Raising Activities, 11/21/68 (Folder 65, Box 3)
  - Memo 12/6/68 (Folder 66, Box 3)
  - Memo to Scenic Hudson Committee Members, 12/19/68 (Folder 67, Box 3)
  - Memo re: Fund-Raising Program for SHPC, 1968-69 (Folder 68, Box 3)
  - Memo to SHPC Board Members, 1/16/69 (Folder 69, Box 3)
  - Memo to Scenic Hudson Directors&Officers, 2/7/69 (Folder 70, Box 3)
  - Special Memo to all Scenic Hudson Committee Members, 4/25/69 (Folder 71, Box 3)
  - Memo to Board Members from Rod Vandivert, 10/9/69 (Folder 72, Box 3)
  - Memo re: Finances and Program, 10/21/69 (Folder 73, Box 3)
  - Memo re: Fortune Magazine on the Environment, 1/30/70 (Folder 74, Box 3)
  - Memo re: Henry Diamond’s Storm King Decision, 8/27/71 (Folder 75, Box 3)
  - Memo to Conservation Leaders (Folder 76, Box 3)
  - SHPC Meeting - Agenda, 2/16/67 (Folder 1, Box 4)
  - SHPC Meeting, 5/10/67 (Folder 2, Box 4)
  - Notice of Meeting, 5/11/67 (Folder 3, Box 4)
  - SHPC Meeting, 5/15/67 (Folder 4, Box 4)
  - SHPC Meeting - Agenda, 5/15/67 (Folder 5, Box 4)
  - SHPC Meeting, 5/22/67 (Folder 6, Box 4)
  - Notes from Octagon House Meeting, 7/11/67 (Folder 7, Box 4)
  - SHPC Meeting, 1/31/68 (Folder 8, Box 4)
  - SHPC Meeting, 5/16/68 (Folder 9, Box 4)
  - Notice of Meeting, 9/11/68 (Folder 10, Box 4)
  - SHPC Meeting, 10/18/68 (Folder 11, Box 4)
  - SHPC Meeting - Agenda, 11/21/68 (Folder 12, Box 4)
  - SHPC Meeting - Agenda, 12/19/68 (Folder 13, Box 4)
  - SHPC Meeting - Agenda, 1/16/69 (Folder 14, Box 4)
  - SHPC Meeting, 3/20/69 (Folder 15, Box 4)
  - Rod Vandivert - Recommendations for Board Meeting, 4/17/69 (Folder 16, Box 4)
  - SHPC Meeting - Agenda&Financial Report, 4/17/69 (Folder 17, Box 4)
  - SHPC Meeting - Agenda, 7/17/69 (Folder 18, Box 4)
  - SHPC Meeting, 8/21/69 (Folder 19, Box 4)
  - SHPC Meeting, 10/16/69 (Folder 20, Box 4)
  - SHPC Meeting, 12/18/69 (Folder 21, Box 4)
  - SHPC Meeting, 1/15/70 (Folder 22, Box 4)
  - Notice of Meeting, 12/19/? And 3/19/? (Folder 23, Box 4)
  - SHPC Anticipated Costs in August&Sept. 1967 (Folder 24, Box 4)
  - SHPC Expenditures by Month, 1967 (Folder 25, Box 4)
  - SHPC Budget Considerations, 1968 (Folder 26, Box 4)
  - Financial Report, 5/16/68 (Folder 27, Box 4)
  - Financial Statement, 8/16 - 9/1&9/1 to Present (1968) (Folder 28, Box 4)
  - Financial Statement, 10/18 - 10/31/68 (Folder 29, Box 4)
  - Financial Statement, 11/1/68 - 11/21/68 (Folder 30, Box 4)
  - Financial Statement, 11/22/68 - 12/19/68 (Folder 31, Box 4)
  - SHPC Financial Statement, 6/19/69 - 7/17/69 (Folder 32, Box 4)
  - SHPC Budget Analysis, 9/24/69 (Folder 33, Box 4)
  - SHPC Financial Statement, 9/19/69 - 10/16/69 (Folder 34, Box 4)
  - SHPC Financial Statement, 11/21/69 - 12/18/69 (Folder 35, Box 4)
  - Financial Statement, 12/19/69 - 1/15/70 (Folder 36, Box 4)
  - SHPC Financial Statement, 1/16/70 - 2/19/70 (Folder 37, Box 4)
  - SHPC Release, 2/14/66 (Folder 38, Box 4)
  - SHPC Release, 3/8/66 (Folder 39, Box 4)
  - SHPC Release, 4/8/66 (Folder 40, Box 4)
  - SHPC Release, 4/22/66 (Folder 41, Box 4)
  - SHPC Release, 5/18/66 (Folder 42, Box 4)
  - SHPC Release, 10/22/66 (Folder 43, Box 4)
  - SHPC Release, 1/13/67 (Folder 44, Box 4)
  - SHPC Release, 2/7/67 (Folder 45, Box 4)
  - SHPC Release, 2/10/67 (Folder 46, Box 4)
  - SHPC Release, 3/21/67 (Folder 47, Box 4)
  - SHPC Release, 3/28/67 (Folder 48, Box 4)
  - SHPC Release, 1/30/68 (Folder 49, Box 4)
  - SHPC Release, 2/15/68 (Folder 50, Box 4)
  - SHPC Release, 1/7/69 (Folder 51, Box 4)
  - SHPC Release, 8/15/69 (Folder 52, Box 4)
  - SHPC Release, 8/29/69 (Folder 53, Box 4)
  - SHPC Release, 5/5/70 (Folder 54, Box 4)
  - SHPC Release, 7/19/? (Folder 55, Box 4)
  - SHPC Release, 7/18/? (Folder 56, Box 4)
  - SHPC Release, 8/14/? (Folder 57, Box 4)
  - SHPC Release, 10/18/? (Folder 58, Box 4)
  - Tarrytown House Meeting, Nov. 18th and 19th 1967 (Folder 1, Box 5)
  - Reservation Card for Tarrytown House Meeting, 11/18& 11/19/68 (Folder 2, Box 5)
  - Cruise up the Hudson on Miss Circle Line, 11/18/68 (Folder 3, Box 5)
  - R.F.K. Statement on Board Miss Circle Line, 11/18/68 (Folder 4, Box 5)
  - Invitation, “Come w/ Us Up the Hudson River” 11/18/68 (Folder 5, Box 5)
  - Partial List of Invitees to 1967 Conference of SHPC (Folder 6, Box 5)
  - Guest List for 1967 Conference (Folder 7, Box 5)
  - Acceptances to Date for 1967 Conference (Folder 8, Box 5)
  - 1967 Conference Program (Folder 9, Box 5)
  - Guest List for 1969 Conservation Dinner (Folder 10, Box 5)
  - Invitations to SHPC Conservation Dinner - May 26, 1969 (Folder 11, Box 5)
  - Seating List for 1969 SHPC Conservation Dinner (Folder 12, Box 5)
  - SHPC Position Statement for 1969 Citizens Conservation (Folder 13, Box 5)
  - 1969 Citizens Conservation Dinner Program (Folder 14, Box 5)
  - 1969 Citizens Conservation Dinner Program w/ a Photo of Russell E. Train&Sen. Whitney N. Seymour Jr. (Folder 15, Box 5)
  - SHPC Sponsoring Committee, As of 10/4/67 (Folder 16, Box 5)
  - SHPC Officers, Executive Committee, Advisory Committee, &Development Committee (Folder 17, Box 5)
  - SHPC Advisory Committee&Executive Committee (Folder 18, Box 5)
  - Development Committee Workers (Folder 19, Box 5)
  - SHPC Committee Outline (Folder 20, Box 5)
  - Citizens Organizing Committee (List) for Letter of Thanks for Helping (Folder 21, Box 5)
  - Mailing List (Folder 22, Box 5)
  - Large Contributions to Scenic Hudson ($50 and Up) 12/2/66 (Folder 23, Box 5)
  - List of Large Contributors to SHPC, 10/5/66 (Folder 24, Box 5)
  - Large Contributors to SHPC ($50 and Up) 1966&1967 (Folder 25, Box 5)
  - Top/Tip Top Special Gift Prospects for SHPC, 1966& 1967 (Folder 26, Box 5)
  - Scenic Hudson Contributors to be Followed up for Larger Contributions, 5/10/67 (Folder 27, Box 5)
  - Special Gift Prospects for SHPC, 9/27/67 (Folder 28, Box 5)
  - Special Gift Prospects for SHPC, 3/14/68 (Folder 29, Box 5)
  - SHPC Confidential Contributors List (Folder 30, Box 5)
  - Tip/Tip Top Special Gift Prospects for SHPC (Folder 31, Box 5)
  - Contributors and Friends of SHPC (Folder 32, Box 5)
  - Con Ed Stock Holders Who Have Contributed to SHPC (Folder 33, Box 5)
  - Please Note the Following Contributions (Folder 34, Box 5)
  - SHPC Position Report, March 1966 (Folder 1, Box 6)
  - Action Letter…A New Storm King Crisis - The Palisades Park, Letters and Calls Needed (Folder 2, Box 6)
  - SHPC Fund-Raising Activities, 5/15/67 (Folder 3, Box 6)
  - SHPC Progress Report, 1968 (Folder 4, Box 6)
  - SHPC Copy of General Fund-Raising Letter (Folder 5, Box 6)
  - 1968 National Conservation Achievement Program (Folder 6, Box 6)
  - SHPC Budget Info, 6/12/67 (Folder 7, Box 6)
  - SHPC Pamphlet “Con Ed Must Not Build at Storm King” (Folder 8, Box 6)
  - “Remember the Hudson River” (Folder 9, Box 6)
  - Letter on Behalf of SHPC by Cornelia Otis Skinner - Soliciting Donations, 8/4/69 (Folder 10, Box 6)
  - SHPC Appeal Letter, Fall 1966 (Folder 11, Box 6)
  - SHPC Letter Soliciting Donations (Folder 12, Box 6)
  - Invitations to Scenic Hudson Events (Folder 13, Box 6)
  - SHPC Capsule Report, 10/11/66 (Folder 14, Box 6)
  - Progress Report, Scenic Hudson Events for 1970 (Folder 15, Box 6)
  - Issue - Preservation of the Scenic Hudson Gorge (Folder 16, Box 6)
  - Excerpt from “Fortune”&SHPC Response, 3/66 (Folder 17, Box 6)
  - Events for Scenic Hudson in the New York Area (Folder 18, Box 6)
  - SHPC Program Outline As of 8/13/69 - History of River Through Song (Folder 19, Box 6)
  - SHPC Job Assignments for Rod Vandivert, 6/19/67 (Folder 20, Box 6)
  - SHPC We Need Immediate Help, 11/21/68 (Folder 21, Box 6)
  - SHPC Answer to Electrical World Ad in the N.Y. Times, 10/6/69 (Folder 22, Box 6)
  - Scenic Hudson Preservation Conference - Deserves Your Support (Folder 23, Box 6)
  - A Friend of the River - SHPC (Folder 24, Box 6)
  - SHPC Presents Humanity’s River (Folder 25, Box 6)
  - List of Interventions on the Side of SHPC (Folder 26, Box 6)
  - Discussion: Creation of a National Trust (Pamphlet) (Folder 27, Box 6)
  - SHPC Reply Card to Mr. Nueberger, Mrs. Davidson,& Mr. Gilmore (Folder 28, Box 6)
  - SHPC - An Urgent Report&Request, 1/10/67 (Folder 29, Box 6)
  - SHPC Special&Urgent, 9/30/66 (Folder 30, Box 6)
  - Costs of Alternative Facilities, Fund-Raising Report, Personnel Recommendations, 10/2/69 (Folder 31, Box 6)
  - Some Proposals for SHPC, 9/19/68 (Folder 32, Box 6)
  - Luce Letters (Folder 33, Box 6)
  - Important Notice…Contributions, 7/1/66 (Folder 34, Box 6)
  - Letter to Citizens - Winter 1973 (Folder 35, Box 6)
  - Letter on Behalf of SHPC by Beatrice Abbot Duggan - Soliciting Donations, 4/12/66 (Folder 36, Box 6)
  - Estimate of Costs for SHPC Mailing Materials (Folder 37, Box 6)
  - A Petition to the FPC by Members&Supporters of SHPC (Folder 38, Box 6)
  - SHPC - The Year of Decision (Folder 39, Box 6)
  - SHPC History&Statement of Position (Folder 40, Box 6)
  - SHPC List of Affiliated Organizations (Folder 41, Box 6)
  - SHPC - Events to Focus Attention on Hudson Highlands (Folder 42, Box 6)
  - SHPC - Pamphlet (Undated) (Folder 43, Box 6)
  - Prototype for SHPC Letterhead, Envelopes, Postcards, etc… (Folder 44, Box 6)
  - SHPC Guide Sheet - May Mailings (Folder 45, Box 6)
  - SHPC New York Times Clipping w/ Bulletin 15, 1966 (Folder 46, Box 6)
  - Report from SHPC 1970-71 (Folder 47, Box 6)
  - SHPC Latest Flash Bulletin (Folder 48, Box 6)
  - SHPC Late News Flash (Folder 49, Box 6)
  - Misc. SHPC - Envelopes, Reply Cards (Folder 50, Box 6)
  - SHPC Misc. Notes (Folder 51, Box 6)
  - SHPC Notes, Drafts of Letters, Mailing Lists, Misc. SHPC (Folder 52, Box 6)
- 4. Printed Matter, 1962 - 1969; 4; 0.6 Linear Feet Boxes: 7 - 8
  Materials on the Hudson River, National Geographic, Action for Clean Waters, Reports, The Cornwall Project, HRVC, etc.
  Roughly by subject
  - National Geographic, March 1962 (Folder 1, Box 7)
  - Report on Pollution of the Hudson River&Its Tributaries, 9/65 (Folder 2, Box 7)
  - Today and Tomorrow in Air Pollution (Folder 3, Box 7)
  - The Waterfront (Folder 4, Box 7)
  - Progress Report - Water Pollution Control, N.Y.S. 9/65 - 9/67 (Folder 5, Box 7)
  - The Manhattan Waterfront Prospects&Problems, 4/65 (Folder 6, Box 7)
  - Cornwall News and Views (A Con Ed Public Information Service) 3/18/66 (Folder 7, Box 7)
  - The Cornwall Project, The Truth vs. 20 Unfounded Charges - Con Ed, 1967 (Folder 8, Box 7)
  - Con Ed Regional Planning, Save Our Deteriorating Environment (Folder 9, Box 7)
  - Lectures on Water Conservation, Report #7, Oct. 1968 (Folder 10, Box 7)
  - Save Cayuga Lake, Newsletters #2, Nov. 1968 (Folder 11, Box 7)
  - The Hudson River Lighthouses (Folder 12, Box 7)
  - Focus on the Hudson (Folder 13, Box 7)
  - Developing&Managing the Water Resources of N.Y.S. (Folder 14, Box 7)
  - Tourist Guide to the Hudson Valley (Folder 15, Box 7)
  - Sierra Club Bulletin (Folder 16, Box 7)
  - The Cornwall Hydroelectric Project - Power&Beauty for Tomorrow (Folder 17, Box 7)
  - Cornwall Pumped Storage Project (Folder 18, Box 7)
  - Government Land Acquisition, New York Edition (Folder 19, Box 7)
  - Reader’s Digest “America the Formerly Beautiful” (Folder 20, Box 7)
  - S.H.P.C. Pamphlet “Are You a Misinformed Birdwatcher, Nature Faker, Land Grabber… (Folder 21, Box 7)
  - How Can I Help the Hudson? (Folder 22, Box 7)
  - S.H.P.C. Strom King Pamphlet (Folder 23, Box 7)
  - The Argonaut - Vol. XVI no. 4, Vol. XVII no. 1&5 (Folder 24, Box 7)
  - Con Ed Pamphlets - “Power for Tomorrow” “The Cornwall Project” (Folder 25, Box 7)
  - “If You’re Unhappy About New York Air, We’re Twice as Unhappy” Con Ed (Folder 26, Box 7)
  - National Parks Association (Folder 27, Box 7)
  - Scenic Hudson Preservation Conference Deserves Your Support (Folder 28, Box 7)
  - “The Time is Now” The Hudson River Conservation Society, Inc. (Folder 29, Box 7)
  - Cluster Development by William H. Whyte (Folder 30, Box 7)
  - Grand Canyon of the Living Colorado (Folder 31, Box 7)
  - Action for Clean Waters (Folder 32, Box 7)
  - Joint Legislative Committee on National Resources, 1965 Annual Report (Folder 33, Box 7)
  - What is…The Hudson River Valley Commission? (Folder 34, Box 7)